[
  {
    "question": "According to Chapter 5 of Solar Storms, elders believe all of the following organisms observe human lives EXCEPT",
    "a": "spiders",
    "b": "dragonflies",
    "c": "birds",
    "d": "mosses",
    "e": "trees",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does LaRue Marks Time have bad luck while fishing?",
    "a": "He gives up too easily.",
    "b": "He wears attention-getting colors.",
    "c": "He does not respect living things.",
    "d": "He makes too much noise.",
    "e": "He chooses the wrong places to fish.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 6 of Solar Storms, how does Angel break her mirror?",
    "a": "She sits on it after forgetting it.",
    "b": "She smashes it with her fist.",
    "c": "She throws it at a wall.",
    "d": "She kicks it.",
    "e": "She drops it on the floor.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 6 of Solar Storms, Angel develops the power to",
    "a": "make maize grow",
    "b": "see through water",
    "c": "ward off storms",
    "d": "call fish to her",
    "e": "listen to bears' songs",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Fur Island seem to play music during Chapter 6 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "Waves lapping on the shore form rhythms.",
    "b": "Abandoned organ pipes make sounds in the wind.",
    "c": "The lowing of caribou creates harmonies.",
    "d": "Water rushes musically over cracked ice.",
    "e": "The raindrops make patterns like drumming.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Chapter 6 of Solar Storms, how did an elder rid his homeland of copper seekers?",
    "a": "He disguised the copper as ordinary rocks.",
    "b": "He drew a misleading map to send them far away.",
    "c": "He played on their greed to make them destroy each other.",
    "d": "He sabotaged their boat so it would drown them.",
    "e": "He poisoned their food so they would die while traveling.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 6 of Solar Storms, Angel links all of the following colors to the cardinal directions EXCEPT",
    "a": "blue",
    "b": "red",
    "c": "yellow",
    "d": "white",
    "e": "black",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was the forest behind the Hundred-Year-Old Road not logged?",
    "a": "A war broke out and the loggers went into the military.",
    "b": "A state park was established in the area.",
    "c": "A new landowner held off on harvesting the place.",
    "d": "A famine starved the loggers and drove them out.",
    "e": "A disease broke out in camp and killed the loggers.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Hannah first arrives at Agnes's house as a girl, she has only her clothes and a(n)",
    "a": "dowsing rod",
    "b": "comb",
    "c": "angel pin",
    "d": "basket",
    "e": "eagle feather",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Hannah steal clothes from various homes and layer them?",
    "a": "She had no money to purchase clothing.",
    "b": "She was a kleptomaniac, driven by compulsion.",
    "c": "She wanted to see others suffer loss.",
    "d": "She was creating a false but better past for herself.",
    "e": "She wore them as armor against being abused.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 6 of Solar Storms, how do the Old Man's actions show the seriousness of Hannah's situation?",
    "a": "He skips the usual social rituals before the visitor asks for help.",
    "b": "He tells Agnes to take Hannah to a priest.",
    "c": "He sings a song that threatens to kill him.",
    "d": "He orders Hannah out of his house.",
    "e": "He refuses to look at Hannah while treating her.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Old Man call Hannah 'the meeting place'?",
    "a": "She unites others in revulsion of her.",
    "b": "She is a nexus or summation of wrongs done to her people.",
    "c": "She draws various people into helping her.",
    "d": "She emerged from the waters that are the Navel of the World.",
    "e": "She brings together the clothing of various families.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Chapter 7 of Solar Storms, how does Bush destroy harmful spirit bridges?",
    "a": "She harvests medicinal plants from her garden.",
    "b": "She sings a specific song.",
    "c": "She creates potions from the milkstone's waters.",
    "d": "She assembles animal skeletons.",
    "e": "She makes offerings to the Hungry Mouth of Water.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Solar Storms, how did Bush's dog die?",
    "a": "Bush euthanized it.",
    "b": "It drowned in the Hungry Mouth of Water.",
    "c": "Hannah tortured and killed it.",
    "d": "It ate a trapper's poison set out for foxes.",
    "e": "LaRue shot it in self-defense.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7 of Solar Storms, Angel compares her sewing struggles to the Greek myth of",
    "a": "Artemis",
    "b": "Athena",
    "c": "Psyche",
    "d": "Ares",
    "e": "Pandora",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the trapper in Chapter 8 of Solar Storms get girls to live with him?",
    "a": "He acts as if he is helping them.",
    "b": "He presents himself as being more successful than he is.",
    "c": "He bribes their families with food and furs.",
    "d": "He abducts them after promises of marriage.",
    "e": "He threatens their families.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does the midwife leave Hannah alone with Angel?",
    "a": "She cannot stand Hannah’s screaming.",
    "b": "She goes to get the food in her car.",
    "c": "She needs to clear snow off the roof.",
    "d": "She has to seek medical attention.",
    "e": "She must return to her own children.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 8 of Solar Storms, while the midwife is away, Hannah has",
    "a": "doused the fire",
    "b": "torn all her clothes",
    "c": "scarred Angel",
    "d": "eaten the last of the food",
    "e": "cut off her hair",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fur Island is located in the middle of",
    "a": "Lake Grand",
    "b": "Lake Perdition",
    "c": "Lake of the Woods",
    "d": "Lake Superior",
    "e": "Lake Huron",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 9 of Solar Storms, Angel witnesses a wolf pack stalking and killing a",
    "a": "moose",
    "b": "bear",
    "c": "beaver",
    "d": "fox",
    "e": "caribou",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "To meet her half-sister, Angel travels to",
    "a": "Utah",
    "b": "South Dakota",
    "c": "Texas",
    "d": "Virginia",
    "e": "Wyoming",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Angel travel to meet her half-sister?",
    "a": "She hitchhikes with strangers.",
    "b": "She steals a car and drives it there.",
    "c": "She takes a Greyhound bus.",
    "d": "She stows away on an interstate train.",
    "e": "She rides with a foster mother.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Angel not give her half-sister the bracelet she brought as a present?",
    "a": "She worries her half-sister will cut herself on its sharp edges.",
    "b": "She is offended by her half-sister’s comments about her scars.",
    "c": "She has to run from the law before giving the bracelet.",
    "d": "She discovers that her half-sister has disfigured hands.",
    "e": "She realizes that the design would offend her half-sister.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the real-life historical incidents mentioned in Chapter 9 of Solar Storms is the killing of the Lakota man",
    "a": "Edgar Bear Runner",
    "b": "Raymond Yellow Thunder",
    "c": "Richard Two Elk",
    "d": "Tom B.K. Goldtooth",
    "e": "Wesley Bad Heart Bull",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Bush date the replica map in Chapter 9 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "The map has Fur Island as two separate islands.",
    "b": "The map depicts a lake that fur traders drained.",
    "c": "The map includes an ancient beaver dam, long since lost.",
    "d": "The map shows a great river as a small stream.",
    "e": "The map corresponds to a period without the Northern Lights.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 9 of Solar Storms, why does Angel view Tommy as more mature than boys she has known in the past?",
    "a": "He listens to old music.",
    "b": "He is tall for his age.",
    "c": "He keeps his household fed.",
    "d": "He once traveled to Europe.",
    "e": "He owns a car.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Angel judge the ice-fishers in Chapter 9 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "She checks whether they kill the fish quickly.",
    "b": "She observes how tidy their shacks are.",
    "c": "She notes their taste in music.",
    "d": "She assesses their clothing.",
    "e": "She eavesdrops on their conversations.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 9 of Solar Storms, how does Angel interrupt Bush’s and LaRue’s business breakup?",
    "a": "She pretends to be in pain.",
    "b": "She drops an assembled animal skeleton.",
    "c": "She slaps LaRue’s face.",
    "d": "She hurries to bring coffee.",
    "e": "She screams at them to stop.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the end of Chapter 9 of Solar Storms, Angel",
    "a": "steals Tommy’s vehicle",
    "b": "admires LaRue’s mummies",
    "c": "flirts with LaRue",
    "d": "makes out with Tommy",
    "e": "interferes in Bush’s love life",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 9 of Solar Storms, Angel’s insistence on telling Dora-Rouge of Bush’s plans ends when",
    "a": "Bush hurts her foot and cannot walk",
    "b": "the Northern Lights appear in the sky",
    "c": "John Husk brings them gasoline for the generator",
    "d": "the Warm Spot freezes over for the first time",
    "e": "LaRue arrives at the Black House with a map",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  }
]